An immortal battle for supremacy.
Underworld is a fantasy, action, thriller film directed by Len Wiseman.
Vampires and werewolves have waged a nocturnal war
against each other for centuries.
But all bets are off when a female vampire warrior named Selene, who's famous for her strength and
werewolf-hunting prowess, becomes smitten with a peace-loving male werewolf, Michael, who wants to end the war.
Selene, played by Kate Beckinsale.
Michael Corvin, played by Scott Speedman.
Lucian, played by Michael Sheen.
Kraven, played by Shane Brolly.
Viktor, played by Bill Nighy.
Singe, played by Erwin Leder.
Underworld is a 2003 action horror film directed by Len Wiseman in his feature film directorial debut, from
a screenplay by Danny McBride, based on a story by Kevin Grevioux, Wiseman, and McBride.
The film stars Kate Beckinsale, Scott Speedman, Michael
Sheen, Shane Brolly, Erwin Leder, and Bill Nighy.
The plot centers on the secret history of vampires and lycans (an
abbreviated form of lycanthrope, which means werewolf).
The main plot revolves around Selene (Beckinsale), a
vampire Death Dealer hunting Lycans.
She finds herself attracted to a human, Michael Corvin
(Speedman), who is being targeted by the Lycans.
After Michael is bitten by a Lycan, Selene must decide whether to do her
duty and kill him or go against her clan and save him.
Underworld premiered at the Grauman's Chinese Theatre in Los Angeles, California on September 15,
2003, and was released in the United States on September 19, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics.
A surprise hit, the film grossed over $95 million worldwide against a
production budget of $22 million and originated a franchise.
The film was followed by Underworld: Evolution in 2006.
The film explores themes of budapest, hungary, love of
one's life, vampire, subway, hostility.
The tone is dark and intense.